<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>CB Wine</title>
	<atom:link href="https://cbwine.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://cbwine.com</link>
	<description>Fine Wine Specialists</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 10:18:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-GB</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/cropped-CAB-favicon-square-logo-32x32.png</url>
	<title>CB Wine</title>
	<link>https://cbwine.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>An Ode to Sauvignon Blanc</title>
		<link>https://cbwine.com/articles/an-ode-to-sauvignon-blanc/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sterling Weston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 10:17:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cbwine.com/?p=22508</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Wild White. This is the translation of Sauvignon Blanc, hailing first from somewhere amidst the uncultivated overgrowths of France. When I think of the wild white sauvage, it is the crisp, fresh gramineous aromatics which first come to mind – so often the cause of its lauding. From the tangled and remote French wilderness, to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em>Wild White.</em> This is the translation of Sauvignon Blanc, hailing first from somewhere amidst the uncultivated overgrowths of France. When I think of the wild white sauvage, it is the crisp, fresh gramineous aromatics which first come to mind – so often the cause of its lauding. From the tangled and remote French wilderness, to being the third most planted white grape after both Chardonnay and Airén, Sauvignon Blanc has ventured its way across the globe like a roaming vagabond, ready to absorb the traits of its terroir.   </p>



<p>It was first discovered in either Bordeaux – a region which, despite its reputation as a land of exquisite reds, actually once predominately produced white wines, before the devastating frosts of 1956 that is – or, over in the Loire Valley, where it is still abundant today. Its reputation in the latter lingers, and is perhaps best known from the Pouilly-Fumé AOC, where it prominently displays its distinct crisp and grassy style, with a slight smokey finish – hence fumé, fumes, smoke. &nbsp;</p>



<p>As is ever the fate of a <em>starry-eyed</em> vagabond, it searches the earth not only to discover further the world outside it, but, whether intentionally or not, to encounter internal changes along the way. When it reaches the warm maritime climates of New Zealand for example, the increased heat expedites its ripening, and beckons forth brighter and fruitier notes: think pineapple, gooseberry, citrus, melon, etc. and with plenty of ‘zippy’ and sometimes sharp acidity. In fact, New Zealand started the trend of the Sauvignon Blanc Day this piece celebrates, which coincides with the onset of spring, and the warmer weather within which a crisp, citrusy and refreshing wine such as this is perhaps best enjoyed. It first visited New Zealand in the 1970s as an experiment, a potential grape to be blended alongside Müller-Thurgau – just as the aforementioned vagabond searches for connection. It is in these lands where it has made a reputation for itself, and every supermarket today has its shelves stacked with options. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Before its journey to the antipodal lands of New Zealand and Australia, it first made a visit to the U.S.A., specifically California in the 1880s at the hands of Charles Wetmore, founder of the award winning Cresta Blanca Winery (now owned by Wente Vineyards), the first Californian winery to win an award at a French wine competition, securing the Grand Prix with its first ever vintage, which, as you may have already guessed, was made from Sauvignon Blanc. He had brought the cuttings from the Sauternes vineyards of Château d'Yquem, (a name which likely needs no introduction), and planted them within the Livermore Valley AVA. Over the next century, Sauvignon Blanc was becoming less and less popular, and in order to negate this, Robert Mondavi, one of the leading Napa producers, decided to market his own style of oak-aged Sauvignon Blanc, doing so under the name Fumé Blanc (borrowed from Pouilly-Fumé), allowing him to side-step the not-quite-negative, but diminished connotations which its prior agnomen carried. Of course, by today, it has more than regained its reputation. Somewhere between then and its arrival in New Zealand, it stopped along the way in South Africa. In both these places (South Africa and the U.S.A.), it tends to be slightly ‘riper’ tasting than in Oceania, developing more stone-fruit notes and roundness, partially due to the prevalence of oak, which is less common over in New Zealand and Australia. &nbsp;</p>



<p>One of the best New World Sauvignon Blancs I have had in a long time was New Zealand producer Spinyback’s 2023 vintage, which I tried at the Berkmann Cellars tasting this year, and it is astonishingly affordable. An intensely aromatic wine, which instantly regaled me with aromas of kiwi just from being poured, which were backed-up on the palate; intense but elegant notes of lime, gooseberry, passionfruit, and slightly unripe mango danced on the palate, with a surprisingly long finish, and a great – I mean really great – balance of sweetness and acidity. Not only is it a wallet-friendly choice, but it was a wine which really stayed with me for the rest of the day, expertly marrying the new world fruit notes, with those classic, timeless traits of the wild white sauvage. &nbsp; &nbsp;</p>



<p></p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">London, 2nd May, MMXXV</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>10 Questions with Jane Renwick</title>
		<link>https://cbwine.com/articles/10-questions-with-jane-renwick/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sophie Burleigh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 09:35:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cbwine.com/?p=18210</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[London City Bond Director In the world of fine wine logistics, few names carry the weight and influence of Jane Renwick, Director at London City Bond (LCB). With decades of experience navigating the intricacies of storage, distribution, and customer service at the highest levels, Jane has become a vital figure in the UK’s wine and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">London City Bond Director</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1024" height="1013" src="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Jane-Renwick-Interview-1-1-1024x1013.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-18212" srcset="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Jane-Renwick-Interview-1-1-1024x1013.jpeg 1024w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Jane-Renwick-Interview-1-1-300x297.jpeg 300w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Jane-Renwick-Interview-1-1-768x760.jpeg 768w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Jane-Renwick-Interview-1-1-1536x1520.jpeg 1536w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Jane-Renwick-Interview-1-1-2048x2027.jpeg 2048w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Jane-Renwick-Interview-1-1-scaled.jpeg 2560w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>Left: CB Wine Director, Enzo Giannotta / Right: LCB Director, Jane Renwick</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>In the world of fine wine logistics, few names carry the weight and influence of Jane Renwick, Director at London City Bond (LCB). With decades of experience navigating the intricacies of storage, distribution, and customer service at the highest levels, Jane has become a vital figure in the UK’s wine and spirits industry. Known for her deep understanding of the sector, she’s helped shape LCB into the trusted logistics partner it is today, and has forged the excellent partnership between us at CB Wine and LCB, allowing our clients to benefit from the highest quality fine wine storage the UK has to offer. We had the pleasure of sitting down with Jane for a 10-question interview, where she shared her insights on the evolution of the wine trade, the future of bonded warehousing, and exciting new developments at the Eton Park site, such as virtual tours...</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>As a client, how do I know my wine is being stored correctly?</strong></li>
</ol>



<p>As a client, you can be confident that your wine is being stored correctly due to several measures we have in place. Our team consists of long-serving, fully trained professionals, many of whom have completed the Wine &amp; Spirit Education Trust (WSET) courses and various other training programs, including the Bonded Warehouse Association (BWA) certification, IOSH, and NEBOSH. Additionally, our in-house apprenticeships cover level 3 exercises and procedures, ensuring they possess the necessary expertise to handle and store wine properly. We have implemented strategic procedures that all staff are thoroughly briefed on and have signed off, designed to uphold the highest standards of wine storage.</p>



<p>Our facility is equipped with a high-spec air conditioning system that consistently maintains the optimal temperature and humidity levels throughout the year, which is essential for preserving the quality of the wine. Additionally, the interior of our building is safeguarded from any outside light, with all windows insulated and covered to prevent exposure to UV rays that can degrade the wine. These measures collectively ensure that your wine is stored in optimal conditions, preserving its quality and flavour.</p>



<p></p>



<ol start="2" class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Why LCB over any other bonded warehouse?</strong></li>
</ol>



<p>Choosing London City Bond (LCB) over any other bonded warehouse offers several key benefits. Across our 16 sites, we have over 600 staff, many experts in their field with vast knowledge and experience, ensuring your wine is handled with the utmost care. We provide a wide range of services, including inventory management, photography, to include 360 images, promotional packaging, and relabelling, catering to diverse client needs.</p>



<p>Our warehouses span over 2.4 million square feet across 16 locations, all equipped with advanced security systems and climate control within our fine wine facilities, to ensure your wine is stored in optimal conditions. Each warehouse is protected by integrated physical and electronic surveillance systems, including fire and intruder alarms monitored off-site, ensuring the highest level of security for your valuable inventory.</p>



<p>Our facilities are strategically located, including unique sites like the only drinks tax warehouse within Tilbury Freeport, allowing for rapid container movements and reduced haulage costs. All our warehouses and IT systems are approved by HM Revenue &amp; Customs, meeting the strictest conditions required for bonded storage. We are also proud to be multiple-time recipients of The Drinks Business award for Distribution Company of the Year.</p>



<p>These factors collectively make LCB a superior choice for bonded warehousing, offering unparalleled expertise, comprehensive services, state-of-the-art facilities, and stringent security measures.</p>



<p></p>



<ol start="3" class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>LCB has various sites all over the country; what sets Eton Park apart when it comes to storing investment grade wines on behalf of our clients?</strong></li>
</ol>



<p>At Eton Park, we pride ourselves on our fully trained, long-serving staff who are dedicated to handling and storing fine wines with the utmost care. Our expertise extends to offering high-end condition report photography, ensuring that every detail of your wine collection is meticulously documented.</p>



<p>We also cater to bespoke imagery requests, providing tailored photographic services to meet your specific needs. With the rollout of our 360-degree studio, we can now offer even more detailed and comprehensive images, giving you a complete view of your wine collection from every angle.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="742" src="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/WhatsApp-Image-2025-02-11-at-13.03.43-1-Copy-1024x742.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-18213" srcset="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/WhatsApp-Image-2025-02-11-at-13.03.43-1-Copy-1024x742.jpeg 1024w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/WhatsApp-Image-2025-02-11-at-13.03.43-1-Copy-300x217.jpeg 300w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/WhatsApp-Image-2025-02-11-at-13.03.43-1-Copy-768x556.jpeg 768w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/WhatsApp-Image-2025-02-11-at-13.03.43-1-Copy.jpeg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>At Eton Park, we are excited to soon introduce our innovative concept of virtual tours. As a client, you will receive a personalized video with a spoken guide touring our site and showcasing your cases. This service is ideal for overseas customers or those unable to travel.</p>



<p>Virtual tours offer several benefits, including:</p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li>Convenience: Clients can explore the facility from anywhere in the world, eliminating the need for travel.</li>



<li>Personalization: Each tour can be tailored to the client's specific interests and needs, providing a more engaging experience.</li>



<li>Transparency: Clients can see exactly how their investment-grade wines are stored and managed, building trust and confidence.</li>



<li>Accessibility: Ideal for clients who may have mobility issues or other constraints that prevent them from visiting in person.</li>



<li>Time Efficiency: Virtual tours can be scheduled at the client's convenience, saving time for both the client and the facility staff.</li>
</ol>



<p>These services, combined with our commitment to excellence, make Eton Park the ideal choice for storing and managing your premier wines.</p>



<p></p>



<ol start="4" class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>How many bottles of wine do you store at this location?</strong></li>
</ol>



<p>At Eton Park, we currently store just under 5,000,000 bottles of wine. We have rare and vintage wines in our vast customers collections, some of which are highly sought after. The range within our site, includes vintages spanning across many decades. We understand that for some collectors, these wines hold significant personal and sentimental value, making them priceless in their eyes.</p>



<ol start="5" class="wp-block-list">
<li>In your time with LCB, what sort of expansion have you seen the company undergo?</li>
</ol>



<p>In my time with LCB, I have witnessed significant expansion. When I started, we operated out of seven sites. Since then, we have grown to 16 sites, creating numerous job opportunities and promotions within the company. This growth has also allowed us to enhance the skill sets of our staff within. I've witnessed significant expansion in our award-winning transport and delivery network. We've developed a comprehensive delivery service that spans the entire UK. With a fleet of over 300 vehicles making up to 23,000 deliveries each week, this service has become a crucial component of our business and a key differentiator from our competitors.</p>



<p></p>



<ol start="6" class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>What would you say has been your biggest challenge and biggest win since joining LCB?</strong></li>
</ol>



<p>My biggest win at LCB is difficult to pinpoint to just one achievement. Coming into a very male-dominated role, I am honoured to be the first woman on the board of directors, which was a significant opportunity for me. This role has allowed me to gain a comprehensive view of the business and actively support women through accreditations such as the Bonded Warehouse Association (BWA) Certification, which focuses on customs and excise education. Additionally, I take great pleasure in witnessing my team grow and develop into managers and supervisors. Seeing them gain skills and confidence fills me with immense pride. I have also promoted numerous women into management positions and integrated women into warehouse and logistical roles, as promoting and providing opportunities for women in the wine industry is something I am very passionate about.</p>



<p>My biggest challenges at LCB have been navigating the male-dominated world of the fine wine industry and becoming the only female director on the board.</p>



<p>Additionally, I have overseen the rollout of one of our other sites, the Drakelow Tunnels in Kidderminster. As many of you may know, underground tunnels are ideal for storing wine. Shielded from light and vibrations and maintained at a consistent temperature, these tunnels provide perfect conditions for long-term storage. The name 'Drakelow' means 'dragon’s mound' in Old English, hinting at the rich history of this site. From an Iron Age fort to a Cold War contingency plan, these tunnels have seen it all.</p>



<p>Built into a Worcestershire hillside which boasts perfect natural conditions for wine storage, the network of tunnels stretches for 3.5 miles, offering 285,000 square feet of usable space. We can accommodate up to 800,000 cases here. Our mission was twofold: to honour the site's heritage and to create a high-quality bonded warehouse for our clients.</p>



<p>All work undertaken here has been done with great respect for the nearby heritage and natural landscape. For example, any new development above ground is screened by greenery. Additionally, a former electrical sub-station on the site is being converted into a bat roost, enhancing local biodiversity.</p>



<p></p>



<ol start="7" class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Are there any further plans for LCB expansion, either at Eton Park or across the country?</strong></li>
</ol>



<p>While physical expansions may be some time away, we are actively focusing on technological advancements. We look forward to providing clients with 360-degree photographs and virtual tours. Additionally, we are exploring how AI systems are being utilized in various industries and considering their integration into our operations. Our goal is to future-proof our services and evolve with the times, catering to new-age demographics and buyers.</p>



<p></p>



<ol start="8" class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>How large is the team working at LCB Eton Park?</strong></li>
</ol>



<p>Our team at LCB Eton Park consists of 34 staff members, working across both office and warehouse roles. The office team includes a highly skilled and professional customer services team, as well as a dedicated team responsible for handling inbound stocks, from setup to landing, and managing ARC's via HMRC. We have a dedicated private client executive who strives to ensure the needs of the clients are met whilst exercising her communication skills to provide unrivalled customer service.</p>



<p>Our warehouse team, led by Lee Whittaker, employs a strategic approach to managing tasks. We have teams dedicated to handling inbound and outbound movements, with each movement checked and documented with photos upon arrival and dispatch. Additionally, we have staff members solely dedicated to private clients, ensuring their specific requirements are met. Each member of our staff, across both office and warehouse, is multi-trained in various roles to ensure continuous workflow despite any challenges we may encounter.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img decoding="async" width="478" height="460" src="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Jane-Renwick-2.png" alt="" class="wp-image-18214" srcset="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Jane-Renwick-2.png 478w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Jane-Renwick-2-300x289.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 478px) 100vw, 478px" /></figure></div>


<ol start="9" class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>When someone visits LCB, what can they expect from a typical visit?</strong></li>
</ol>



<p>When clients visit Eton Park, they can expect a comprehensive and professional experience. Visitors are greeted by our friendly and knowledgeable staff, who are ready to assist and provide information about our services. Guests are provided with a tour of our state-of-the-art facilities, showcasing their cases of fine wine. We are proud of our advanced security systems, climate-controlled storage, and the meticulous processes we use to handle and store wine.</p>



<p>During the tour, visitors can also observe our strategic procedures in action, including the handling of inbound and outbound stocks, inventory management, and the detailed documentation process with photographs of arrivals and dispatches. They also have the opportunity to meet our dedicated teams, including customer service representatives, private client executive, and the warehouse staff, all of whom are multi-trained to ensure seamless operations.<br>Additionally, we can have the customer's inventory picked out and ready for inspection by the owners. They are then welcome to view and handle their investments, providing a personal and hands-on experience with their wine collection.</p>



<p></p>



<ol start="10" class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>We were lucky enough to experience your new 360 photography studio today. How important was that new system for what LCB offers its clients?</strong></li>
</ol>



<p>We are delighted that you had the opportunity to experience our new 360 photography studio. This system has been a long-term goal for us, and now that it is fully installed, we can offer something truly innovative to our clients. It provides especially valuable material for our auction house clients and those with premium wines, enhancing the way they present and manage their collections.</p>



<p></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>To see our video tour of the LCB Eton Park site, click <a href="https://www.youtube.com/shorts/yXBi1__vLU4" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here.</a></strong></p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>An Ode to Malbec</title>
		<link>https://cbwine.com/articles/ode-to-malbec/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sterling Weston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 12:13:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cbwine.com/?p=22417</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By Sterling Weston, Events and Trade Representative Malbec is a wine varietal that has seen a lot of ups and downs. Be that the higher acidity but lower tannins; be that going from one of the most planted and loved French wine varietals, to one nearly wiped out and only really seen as a blending [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em>By Sterling Weston, Events and Trade Representative</em></p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img decoding="async" width="601" height="325" src="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image.png" alt="" class="wp-image-22418" srcset="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image.png 601w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-300x162.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 601px) 100vw, 601px" /></figure></div>


<p>Malbec is a wine varietal that has seen a lot of ups and downs. Be that the higher acidity but lower tannins; be that going from one of the most planted and loved French wine varietals, to one nearly wiped out and only really seen as a blending component; or being a newly planted varietal in Argentina, to becoming arguably that nation’s most beloved grape. The story of how it ended up thriving over in South America and coming full circle into the realm of appreciation, is the result of many of these fluctuations.</p>



<p>Having once been prized for its thick dark skins, higher acidity, softer tannins, and a juicy, jammy dark-fruit character, this grape, commonly used to produce Cahor’s ‘Black Wines’, was supposedly a favourite of the Russian and French nobilities. One of the grape’s weaknesses, however, was it susceptibility to disease, suffering numerous Phylloxera plagues over the centuries, as well as its susceptibility to frost, as would be dramatically exemplified in the mid-20th century. The devastating European frosts of 1956, which killed as much as 90% of the vines in some areas, not only caused Bordeaux to go from primarily producing white wine to its now famous reds, but also caused Malbec to essentially recede from French vineyards, being replaced thereafter by the more popular and more frost-resistant Cabernet Sauvignon and Merlot varietals. As unfortunate an event as this plight it was, it is now generally agreed upon that Malbec’s disappearance and subsequent re-emergence across the Atlantic Ocean helped not only create the high-quality Merlot / Cabernet Sauvignon dominated Bordeaux blends of the last 60 years, but also allowed Malbec to shine in what is considered a more suitable climate in South America.</p>



<p>On the 17th of April 1853, French agronomist Michel Aimé Pouget had, after propagating French varietals across the border in Chile with a group of other scientists fleeing Napoleon III, presented to the governmental board of Mendoza his plan to introduce some Malbec cuttings to Argentina, in order to improve the quality of the nation’s wines, and, hopefully as a consequence, their exports as well. He had chosen Malbec, in addition to a few other varietals, because of its predicted suitability to the higher altitudes and warmer climate, both of which, he speculated, would help generate more complexity in the grape, with the altitude increasing acidity, and the warmer climate helping smooth out some of the tannic structure — something for which he would eventually be vindicated.</p>



<p>Ironically, however, as Malbec begun to blossom in the Americas, its popularity had begun to decline in Europe, and, by the aftermath of the aforementioned frost, it was found mostly as a small, if not one of the smallest blend-components across many French and Italian vineyards. This decreasing popularity led the Argentinian farmers to begin up-rooting Malbec vines in favour of Merlot and Cabernet Sauvignon. This replacement would not last too long however, and by the turn of the century many wine lovers the world over began to recognise the thriving of Malbec in Argentina, and, as of today, the nation is accountable for 75% of the world’s Malbec wines, — and for good reason. The Argentinian wines are generally clean, approachable, balanced, fruit-forward, and yet still posses enough complexity and dark-fruit punchiness to stand up with a meal.</p>



<p>This does not, however, confine Malbec to one area. After the frost of 1956, the Cahors region, which was and still is known for its Malbec, was one of the few regions to seriously focus on replanting its vines, and today the Cahors AOC stipulates that Malbec (known as Côt and Auxerrois by the locals) make up no less than 70% of the total wines produced — usually supplemented by Merlot and Tannat. The 100% Malbec wines found here are going to be noticeably… dirtier, than their South American siblings, more notes of dried herbs, wood, slightly smoky undertones, with some stony minerals in the finish, and a more jagged tannic structure, lending them self greatly against more intense lamb or gamey meat pairings. Another less-famous but equally appealing source for unblended Malbec wines is Washington, with a surge of well scoring and unique wines coming from the area, such as Hamilton Cellars, creating award winning Malbecs out of the Red Mountain region.</p>



<p>To have seen Malbec rise, fall, and now rise again, especially with brands like Hamilton Cellars as well as Argentinian classics like Catena Zapata assiduously focused on Malbec, is a great way to celebrate the varietal, and synthesise its past with its undoubtedly bright future.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">London, 17th April, MMXXV</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Colours, tones and textures: An exploration of tasting notes</title>
		<link>https://cbwine.com/articles/colours-tones-and-textures-an-exploration-of-tasting-notes/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sterling Weston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 15:54:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cbwine.com/?p=12252</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What’s in a name?&#160;What’s in a tasting note? Whilst it is true that all the primary senses are engaged when enjoying a wine, taste is, perhaps, the most dominant, and it is this potent element of the experience which we are trying to communicate through the common tool, the ‘tasting note’. Dating back to the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><s>What’s in a name?</s>&nbsp;What’s in a tasting note? Whilst it is true that all the primary senses are engaged when enjoying a wine, taste is, perhaps, the most dominant, and it is this potent element of the experience which we are trying to communicate through the common tool, the ‘tasting note’.</p>



<p>Dating back to the ancient Greeks, we hear stories of Plato and Aristotle starting to categorise the ‘flavour species’ of wine: the sweet, the sour, the salty, the savoury. In England’s Caroline Era, Tobias Whitaker’s text The Blood of the Grape replaced these with: ‘sweet, acute, austere, and milde’. And, by the 20th century, the esteemed Michael Broadbent had solidified — not without the assistance of tradition and colleagues — a rather understated, yet analytical and descriptive nomenclature, of which I shall list one example of his, à-propos the 1961 vintage of Pétrus:</p>



<p><strong><em>Opaque; huge, opulent throughout; sweet, full-bodied, incredibly rich, velvety, warm glowing flavor yet still peppery—needs time.</em></strong></p>



<p>In this style of description, it is clear to see that it centres less on ‘tasting notes’, less on specific ‘ingredients’, and rather around the ‘experience’ of the wine: the colours, tones, textures, characteristics — here we see traces of a common thematic thread, that ultimately wine does not contain any plums, any spices, any black currants or tobacco, so why use these when discussing the wine? On the other hand, when wanting to convey this to a less-experienced taster, one can see the rationale behind utilising approximations, reminiscences. Broadbent’s descriptive style clearly aligns with a communicative method orientated towards other wine critics or sommeliers, and, whilst still proving some benefit to a general consumer, it may to some feel a little too vague. We are likely all familiar with the concepts of velvety, rich, glowing, but appropriating those terms into the context of wine may not be as intuitive as it seems on the surface. When we look at a more typical ‘modern style’ taste-description — the familiar list of real-world ingredients — it is easy to see why this might resonate more with the budding wine drinker, for it gives them something to latch on to, some prior reference, some lens through which they can transpose the wine into an experience bordering the familiar. As a good example of this method, let’s look at Robert Parker’s critical analysis of the same aforementioned ‘61 Pétrus:</p>



<p><strong><em>[…] amber and garnet, but the wine is crammed with viscous, thick, over-ripe black-cherry, mocha-tinged fruit flavors. Extremely full-bodied, […] this unctuously-textured, thick wine makes for an awesome mouthful. Imagine a Reese's Peanut Butter Cup laced with layers of coffee and cherry, and encased in a shell of Valrhona chocolate!</em></strong></p>



<p>Evidently there is something to this specificity… and, recognising the indubitable influence Parker had over the wine community, it is hard to outright deny. The phenomenon of ‘Parkerization’ (if you consider it to be one, that is) shows that the industry, in aggregate, has some appetite for particular descriptors. The words of Robert Parker were so lauded in fact, that they essentially guided not only wine consumption, but wine production as well; if an un-seasoned drinker wanted to purchase a good wine with little to no risk, they would need to look no further than his latest reviews, and, with this influence, so too acquiesced the producers — wanting, of course, to market their wines to this new crowd of eager and dirigible drinkers. This impact, whilst surely over-exaggerated and hyper-focused on Parker by many online, does however highlight the power behind unambiguous tasting notes, and this culture-shift has found its way even into bottle-labelling procedures. Look at the way a classic Bordeaux winery such as Haut-Brion describes their 2017 Premier Cru Classé:</p>



<p><strong><em>Beautiful deep red with purple highlights. The initial impression on the nose is of a very elegant wine made with perfectly mature grapes. Swirling in the glass reveals complex aromas featuring ripe fruit, spices, and liquorice. […] with rich tannin evolving into a wonderfully long aftertaste.</em></strong></p>



<p>Contrast this, say, with the approach of a newly-founded Californian producer, such as Memento Mori and their 2018 Cabernet Sauvignon vintage:</p>



<p><strong><em>Ripe blackberries, crushed boysenberries, black plums, spiced mocha and hints of cassis are backed by touches of black tea, wet stone, cigar box and Indian spices […] A medley of wild blackberries, blueberries and black raspberries frame a sophisticatedly nuanced mid-palate, all wrapped in plush, fine-grained tannins that sit on the palate […].</em></strong></p>



<p>It is clear that both serve their respected purpose, and yet in very different styles. One is modest, reserved, urbane, and simplistic, and the other is bold, daring, opulent, and charged. When you consider that the prior is over 500 years old, and the latter around 15, we see cultural differentiations as well as functional ones; they reinforce the character of the brand, the attitude of the winemakers, and, whether discernible or not, the wines themselves.</p>



<p>Turning now to a more rigid, schematised approach, WSET’s classifications certainly aided this push towards the particular. With a comprehensive framework of descriptors grounded in real-world analogues, we find now generations of wine professionals essentially raised on this method. When your frame of reference for wine is predicated first and foremost upon discovering the prevalence of ‘apple’, ‘passionfruit’, ‘cranberry’, ‘wet stones’, ‘biscuit’, ‘cloves’, or ‘leather’, then of course, when engaging with the wider world of wine, you will seek out these points of comfort, these defining aspects of a wine.</p>



<p>What is trickier to trace than this development of style, however, is the various bifurcations between ‘a critic’ and ‘a drinker’; for it is without doubt that the centuries are full of both. When does a description over-reach its boundary, and become, instead, an interference to the drink?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Between these many evolving and interacting systems, approaches, and personalities, there are essentially two functions for tasting notes, the customer-driven, or ‘intra-industry’ usage, and the wine-driven, or ‘inter-industry’ usage. Where the latter aims at highlighting aspects of the wine likely familiar, or readily-graspable by other experienced tasters, the prior aims to convey the core profile of any given wine to the consumer, thereby guiding the consumer towards the most suitable product for them to purchase. This serves a strict, functional, almost machinic role, and to many on the outside of the industry, this suffices, and there is long unending war about how narrow or broad taste descriptors can or should be. Whilst the concern around using a descriptor like ‘musty piano teacher’ is understandable, any tenable desire requires at least some flexibility.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Glancing over for a moment at the specialty coffee industry is revealing, it is one where only the ‘pleasant’ notes are encouraged on the packaging. In fact, it is frequently debated whether a certain note carries ‘the right connotation’. Although this has an ostensible logic, there is — intentional or not — a veneer of deception too, one that seeks to beguile the potential customer into a manufactured preconception. Here in the wine world, however, we are not only accustomed to, but indeed attracted to the honesty and complexity of rubber, petrol, leather, burnt tobacco, forest floor, farm-yard, etc; I once heard of ‘Polly Pocket clothes’ in response to a very mature Riesling — and that sounds like an exciting wine to try! It is no doubt true that oddities such as these are part of the holistic experience of any given wine, there is, as I said, an honesty here, a love for the weird, an acceptance of the ingredient as it is. But then there is ‘musty piano teacher’… Then, further down the line, there is prolixity and pretentiousness — a stigma already too pervasive in the wine industry.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, as with most things, there is a balance to be had, a balance between evocation and communication, between modesty and aesthetic grandeur, between description and narrative. When reading, hearing, writing, or otherwise engaging with a tasting note, it is important to always consider the utility at hand, the intention of its source… Is it to relate a core experience? is it display a heightened complexity? is it to entertain, tell a story? or is it to reflect the character of the wine beyond just its taste? Whilst it is sensible for one to err on the side of caution, there is a great joy and indeed benefit in being regaled with a more emotional characterisation of a wine, instead of a mere rigid list of ingredients, existing as nothing more than simulacrums. After all:&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><em>‘her laughter: &nbsp; wielding &nbsp; the oak’&nbsp;</em></strong></p>



<p>invokes within me a lot more about the 2020 Louis Latour Corton-Charlemange, than ‘citrus and orchard fruits, honey, creamy, higher than usual acidity, oaky finish’ — and, at the end of the day, it is not as though the prior description is going to end up on a bottle…</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Spotlight on... Johannesburg</title>
		<link>https://cbwine.com/articles/spotlight-on-johannesburg/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sterling Weston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 14:13:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Spotlight]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cbwine.com/?p=11966</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Each month in our ‘Spotlight On…’ series, we explore a new city and its wine culture, diving into the drinking trends, where to go for great wines, and any unique products or services linked to the region. Keeping our finger on the pulse when it comes to the wider world of wine is critical when [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Each month in our ‘Spotlight On…’ series, we explore a new city and its wine culture, diving into the drinking trends, where to go for great wines, and any unique products or services linked to the region. Keeping our finger on the pulse when it comes to the wider world of wine is critical when helping us to identify areas of opportunity for our clients, aiding our eventing arm&nbsp;<a href="https://cbwrapped.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">‘Wrapped’</a>, and for our online product offering on&nbsp;<a href="https://cbuncorked.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Uncorked</a>. Whether curious about the habits and happenings of a city, or looking for wine-centric areas to visit in the area, our ‘Spotlight On…’ series is for you.</p>



<p>Even though Johannesburg is located about 900km from South Africa’s wine growing regions, what it lacks for in vines it certainly makes up for in bars. In fact, the wine culture there has grown so considerably in the past decade, that a couple of years back Star Wine List eventually launched their Wine Guide for the city, highlighting the growing scene. As far as their tastes go, there is a noticeable, and perhaps slightly predictable preoccupation with South African wines, and many of the bars and restaurants are using their presence to establish and showcase smaller producers from the country, especially those using low-intervention wine making, and classic grapes from the area, like Pinotage and Chenin Blanc.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>OVERALL TRENDS</strong></p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Focus on small-batch, local, South African producers.</li>



<li>An appreciation for low-intervention winemaking, and single-varietal wines.</li>



<li>Pan-Asian food is quite popular there, especially with wine-oriented establishments.</li>



<li>Plenty of Champagne and sparkling wines.</li>
</ul>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>WOMEN OF WINE</strong></p>



<p><strong>ACID FOOD &amp; WINE BAR</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="600" height="364" src="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-11968" srcset="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image.jpg 600w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-300x182.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></figure>



<p>Leading the charge in Johannesburg’s focus on small-batch, minimalist, organic wine producers are Acid Food &amp; Wine Bar, founded and run by sommelier Jemma Styer and chef Jes Devoton, who pride themselves on bringing quality, light-heartedness, and ultimately joy to the masses. Much of their wine-list focuses on female-led wineries from the country, something especially important considering the male dominance in South African wine production, as well as the bar and restaurant industry as a whole. Their wine list is rapidly changing, and fresh, given the small quantities produced by their partners, and they even offer every wine by-the-glass in order to foster as much curiosity and freedom as they can when exploring South Africa’s undeniably exciting wine-making.</p>



<p>Their food menu is equally enticing, and utilises Devoton’s Thai heritage to bring in a strong Southeast-Asian influence to their use of local ingredients, and many years of self-taught experience, creating what she herself calls ‘global food’.</p>



<p>They have, unfortunately, temporarily closed their doors whilst they restructure and prepare for the next stage of their evolution — so if you are in the area, keep your eyes peeled for their next steps.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>BAR HOPPING</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" width="269" height="145" src="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-11969" style="width:250px"/></figure>



<p><strong>Ethos</strong></p>



<p>Location: Oxford Parks, Corner Eastwood &amp; Parks Blvd, Rosebank.</p>



<p>Vibe: Grandiose, Mediterranean, educational.</p>



<p>Known for: Highly informative wine-list detailing regions, grapes, techniques, etc.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" width="276" height="153" src="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-11967" style="width:250px"/></figure>



<p><strong>Tang</strong></p>



<p>Location: 120, Nelson Mandela Square, Sandton.</p>



<p>Vibe: Opulent, stylish, refined.</p>



<p>Known for: Seamlessly fusing Asian cuisine with South African wine.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" width="228" height="126" src="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-1.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-11971" style="width:250px"/></figure>



<p><strong>Proud Mary&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>Location: The Bank, 26 Cradock Ave, Rosebank.</p>



<p>Vibe: Modern, Art-Deco, trendy.</p>



<p>Known for: Dedicated wine bar, a fine wine library stock, focus on low-intervention wines.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" width="256" height="142" src="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-2.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-11970" style="width:250px"/></figure>



<p><strong>Embarc</strong></p>



<p>Location: Hyde Park Corner Shopping Centre Jan Smuts &amp; 6th Rd, Hyde Park.</p>



<p>Vibe: Modern, laid-back, elegant.</p>



<p>Known for: Extensive single-varietal wine list, focusing on local producers and South African grapes.</p>



<p></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>EXPRESSION WINES AFRICA</strong></p>



<p><strong>‘Wine Tastes Better When You Understand It’</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" width="602" height="401" src="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-2.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-11972" style="width:500px" srcset="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-2.jpeg 602w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-2-300x200.jpeg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 602px) 100vw, 602px" /></figure>



<p>In 2018, Tawanda Marume, now the South Africa ambassador for Star Wine List and 2020’s Sommelier of the Year in Zimbabwe, moved to Johannesburg to start Expression Wines Africa (EWA), an organisation established with the goal of supporting growth for the South African wine market, be that through teaming up with small, boutique producers, assisting bars and restaurants with their wine lists and training, providing educational resources and events, or simply spreading the word. They live by the motto ‘Wine tastes better when you understand it’, and everything they do is tailored around this. They believe in supporting wines which do not rely on brand-recognition to succeed, but rather are always on the hunt for lesser-known, more exciting, and most importantly delicious wines. Not only is he operating across South Africa, but intends to inject the vibrancy of their wine culture into his homeland of Zimbabwe, which he considers seriously neglected.</p>



<p>Sharing Marume’s passion and excitement for South African wines, we really enjoy looking at their red wines, seeing as they are very much known for their whites, and <a href="https://cbuncorked.com/wine/paserene-union-2019/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>Paserene Union 2019</strong></a><strong> </strong>is a great example of the complexity they can achieve, with a rich tannin structure, plenty of dark ripe fruit, and undertones of smoke, charcoal, wood, and a pleasant bitter floral finish.</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>10 Questions with Lee Whittaker</title>
		<link>https://cbwine.com/articles/10-questions-with-lee-whittaker/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sophie Burleigh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 14:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cbwine.com/?p=9278</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Meet Lee Whittaker, Warehouse Manager for London City Bond's Eton Park location in Derby; The man in charge of the storage, provenance and shipment of our clients' wines. We were lucky enough to interview Lee, gaining insights into the workings of LCB, the wines they store there, and what's on the horizon for the future [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="622" src="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Lee-Whittaker-Article-Copy-1024x622.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-9280" srcset="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Lee-Whittaker-Article-Copy-1024x622.jpeg 1024w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Lee-Whittaker-Article-Copy-300x182.jpeg 300w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Lee-Whittaker-Article-Copy-768x466.jpeg 768w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Lee-Whittaker-Article-Copy-1536x933.jpeg 1536w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Lee-Whittaker-Article-Copy-2048x1244.jpeg 2048w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Lee-Whittaker-Article-Copy-scaled.jpeg 2560w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Meet Lee Whittaker, Warehouse Manager for London City Bond's Eton Park location in Derby; The man in charge of the storage, provenance and shipment of our clients' wines. We were lucky enough to interview Lee, gaining insights into the workings of LCB, the wines they store there, and what's on the horizon for the future of fine wine storage…</p>



<p></p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>How long have you worked for LCB and what did your journey within the company look like?</strong></li>
</ol>



<p>I began my journey here 23 years ago, starting as a Christmas temp in October 2001. By 2002, I was employed full-time. My drive and eagerness to learn led me to work in every department, handling various tasks from condition reports to goods in and out, printing daily orders, and compiling manifests. I excelled in the goods out department and was promoted to team leader. My continuous learning and dedication quickly advanced me to the role of warehouse supervisor.</p>



<p>Throughout the restructuring of Eton Park, I witnessed several managerial changes. When the opportunity arose, I applied for the Warehouse Manager position. With my extensive knowledge of the warehouse operations and a strong desire to grow, I was ready for the challenge. Jane Renwick (London City Bond Director) entrusted me with the role and has been incredibly supportive throughout my journey. Working alongside her, I have gained invaluable experience and knowledge.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="605" src="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/LCB-Visit-Lee-and-Jane-1024x605.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-9281" srcset="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/LCB-Visit-Lee-and-Jane-1024x605.jpeg 1024w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/LCB-Visit-Lee-and-Jane-300x177.jpeg 300w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/LCB-Visit-Lee-and-Jane-768x454.jpeg 768w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/LCB-Visit-Lee-and-Jane-1536x907.jpeg 1536w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/LCB-Visit-Lee-and-Jane-2048x1210.jpeg 2048w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/LCB-Visit-Lee-and-Jane-scaled.jpeg 2560w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>From left to right - Sophie Burleigh [CB Head of Operations] Lee Whittaker [Eton Park Warehouse Manager] Jane Renwick [LCB Director] Enzo Giannotta [CB Founder &amp; Director]</em></p>



<p>My managerial journey began in 2019 and was immediately challenged both personally and professionally. The last conversation I had with my mother before she passed away was to share the news that I had been appointed as manager, a proud moment for both of us. Shortly thereafter, the Covid-19 pandemic struck. As a new manager, I was unfamiliar with the concept of 'furlough,' and we had to operate with only 50% of our staff. With a surge in orders due to more people staying at home, we worked six days a week continuously, making this an exceptionally demanding period.</p>



<p>Once the pandemic subsided, we faced another significant challenge: a large wine merchant we work with would be relocating a huge amount of their stock. We had to meticulously plan the logistics and mobilize our teams to complete the move within the designated timeframe, which we did.</p>



<p>Despite these challenges, I am proud of how we navigated through these tough times. The experience has strengthened our team and enhanced our resilience, preparing us for any future challenges.</p>



<p>Since then, I have continued to learn and grow, supported by Alf Allington, Jane Renwick and the other board of directors, my team, and my own determination to succeed.</p>



<p></p>



<ol start="2" class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>What factors have encouraged you to work at LCB for such a long time?</strong></li>
</ol>



<p>For me, the most significant factor is having the opportunity to grow and mature, being taught, and being given a voice.</p>



<p></p>



<ol start="3" class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>What are the biggest changes you have seen in the company since you started working for LCB?</strong></li>
</ol>



<p>The most significant change I've observed at LCB is our growth. We now have 16 sites across the UK, with five located in the Midlands. Previously, Eton Park was our sole site in the Midlands. The biggest transformation for Eton Park occurred after the relocation of one of our largest client's wines. Before that, we were completely packed, bursting at the seams with stock. Completing this transfer allowed us to have the complete reset we needed.</p>



<p></p>



<ol start="4" class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>The LCB team is committed to continuous improvement at the Eton Park site. What current renovations is the site undergoing?</strong></li>
</ol>



<p>We have already streamlined the floors by clearing aisles and tidying all the bays, which has given us better working space. A larger checking area and a new office has been built for the inbound team within the warehouse, allowing them to make corrections to deliveries and print paperwork at the source. Additionally, we have constructed two new photo studios equipped with state-of-the-art photography equipment. One of these studios features a 360-degree setup, which we plan to roll out very soon. We are actively working throughout the entire warehouse to replace old boarding on the racks. Our maintenance team is rejuvenating all of the site's original features, including the internal window shutters and the large wooden shutter doors, which are being refreshed with a new coat of paint.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="671" src="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/LCB-Article-2-1024x671.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-9282" srcset="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/LCB-Article-2-1024x671.jpeg 1024w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/LCB-Article-2-300x197.jpeg 300w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/LCB-Article-2-768x504.jpeg 768w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/LCB-Article-2-1536x1007.jpeg 1536w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/LCB-Article-2-2048x1343.jpeg 2048w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/LCB-Article-2-scaled.jpeg 2560w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<ol start="5" class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>What has been the biggest challenge and biggest win in your current role with LCB?</strong></li>
</ol>



<p>As I mentioned earlier, the biggest challenge was undoubtedly the Covid lockdowns and restrictions. We operated at 50% capacity, handling upwards of 250 orders per day, and even worked weekends just to make a dent in the backlog. Although it was chaotic, we persevered and learned a lot along the way. One significant innovation was the introduction of 'Bulk picks,' which had never been tested at our site before.</p>



<p>Reflecting on this period, I realize how much it taught us about resilience and adaptability. Despite the overwhelming pressure, our team pulled together and found new ways to overcome obstacles. It was a tough journey, but it strengthened our operations and brought us closer as a team.</p>



<p>I would also highlight staff. As a manager, motivating the team during peak times and navigating new policies and regulations can be challenging.</p>



<p></p>



<ol start="6" class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>When clients organise a private visit to LCB Eton Park to view their wines, what can they expect?</strong></li>
</ol>



<p>Clients visiting Eton Park for a private tour can look forward to an engaging and personalized experience. They will enjoy a comprehensive guided tour of our facility, where they can see firsthand how their wines are meticulously stored and cared for. They will also get an insider's look at all the processes involved, from receiving to dispatching orders. For an even more personalized touch, we can pre-arrange to have the client's wines retrieved from locations for them to view up close. If they wish, we can even open the cases to inspect the collection in detail.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="417" src="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/LCB-Article-3-1024x417.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-9283" srcset="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/LCB-Article-3-1024x417.jpeg 1024w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/LCB-Article-3-300x122.jpeg 300w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/LCB-Article-3-768x313.jpeg 768w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/LCB-Article-3-1536x626.jpeg 1536w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/LCB-Article-3.jpeg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<ol start="7" class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Security and assurance are paramount concerns for our clients when storing their wines- how does the team at LCB ensure the safety of their clients’ wines?</strong></li>
</ol>



<p>The Eton Park facility is fortified with 65 CCTV cameras, strategically placed both internally and externally to cover the entire perimeter. Every stock item that enters or exits the building is meticulously photographed on the pallets, documenting its condition upon arrival and dispatch. Our staff members are highly experienced, with most having completed WSET courses, ensuring expert handling of all stock. The warehouse features a single, highly secure entry and exit point, which is double padlocked every evening. The site itself is protected by a single main entrance through a robust double iron gate, controlled by an intercom system. Additionally, we have onsite security guards who patrol the perimeter throughout the night, providing an extra layer of protection.</p>



<p></p>



<ol start="8" class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>In your opinion, what make Eton Park stand out from other sites?</strong></li>
</ol>



<p>I wouldn’t claim that we stand out from other LCB sites; rather, we are unique in our structure. As a Grade 2 listed building, we face distinct challenges. Our facility spans four floors, accessible by two goods lifts. The design and structure of our building, coupled with a sophisticated air conditioning system, enable us to provide optimal conditions for fine wine storage. When it comes to non-LCB sites, we truly shine with our exceptional staff retention. Most of our team members have been with us for over 10 years, which speaks volumes about our work environment. We proudly offer apprenticeships through our LCB Benefits website, and many of our staff have achieved various university-level qualifications, as well as ISOH, wine verification courses, and photography guides. It's a testament to our commitment to growth.</p>



<p></p>



<ol start="9" class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>With so much wine through the doors, are there any memorable deliveries that stand out to you?</strong></li>
</ol>



<p>One of the most memorable deliveries must be the 'Space X Petrus' inside a massive wooden crate. These bottles went to space with the Elon Musk - SpaceX expedition to monitor how environmental changes affect the wine. And as a huge Bond fan, I can't help but get excited every time we receive the special edition Bollinger James Bond editions.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="880" height="550" src="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Space-X-Petrus.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9284" srcset="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Space-X-Petrus.jpg 880w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Space-X-Petrus-300x188.jpg 300w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Space-X-Petrus-768x480.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 880px) 100vw, 880px" /></figure>



<ol start="10" class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>What is next for LCB Eton Park?</strong></li>
</ol>



<p>Next for Eton Park are continuous and transformative improvements to both our site and the services we provide. During our discussion in the boardroom on your visit, the key phrase that resonated with me was 'Core Values and being the best at the basics.' This is precisely what Eton Park strives for, and we are committed to not only mastering the fundamentals but also pushing the boundaries. Our goal is to set new industry standards and lead the way in innovation and customer satisfaction. We are excited to continue investing in our staff with dynamic and comprehensive training schemes, which significantly boost staff morale and foster a positive, motivated work environment.</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Spotlight on... Florence</title>
		<link>https://cbwine.com/articles/spotlight-on-florence/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sterling Weston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Spotlight]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cbwine.com/?p=7155</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Each month in our ‘Spotlight On…’ series, we explore a new city and its wine culture, diving into the drinking trends, where to go for great wines, and any unique products or services linked to the region. Keeping our finger on the pulse when it comes to the wider world of wine is critical when [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Each month in our ‘Spotlight On…’ series, we explore a new city and its wine culture, diving into the drinking trends, where to go for great wines, and any unique products or services linked to the region. Keeping our finger on the pulse when it comes to the wider world of wine is critical when helping us to identify areas of opportunity for our clients, aiding our eventing arm&nbsp;<a href="https://cbwrapped.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">‘Wrapped’</a>, and for our online product offering on&nbsp;<a href="https://cbuncorked.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Uncorked</a>. Whether curious about the habits and happenings of a city, or looking for wine-centric areas to visit in the area, our ‘Spotlight On…’ series is for you.</p>



<p>As the warmer days approach, we turn our minds to one of Europe’s most visited holiday destinations, Florence, known not only for its abundance of Renaissance architecture, amazing food, and host of museums, but being the heart of Tuscany, it comes of course with plenty of truly amazing wines. Quite a few of us in the CB office have now visited Florence in order to experience its world-class wine culture, and, having loved it, we thought we would share some of our insights.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>OVERALL TRENDS</strong></p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Respect and pride for local Tuscan wines, which most offerings will consist of.</li>



<li>A unique culture of ‘Wine Windows’ scattered across the city.</li>



<li>Plenty of natural, organic, or otherwise sustainable micro-producers.</li>



<li>Celebrating the marriage between Tuscany’s wines and the locally produced food.</li>
</ul>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>WINE WINDOWS</strong></p>



<p><strong>WINE WINDOWS OF FLORENCE</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" width="601" height="401" src="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/image.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-7156" style="width:400px" srcset="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/image.jpg 601w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/image-300x200.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 601px) 100vw, 601px" /></figure>



<p>Perhaps the most famous thing about Florence’s wine scene is the prevalence of the idiosyncratic and much-photographed <em>Buchettas</em>, small windows designed in the 16<sup>th</sup> century for the newly deregulated sale of goods, specifically so that the servants of Florentine’s elite could sell off their Master’s wines in an easy manner, without needing to permit entry to the estate. Due to wine being one of the more common usages, they have become known by foreigners as ‘wine windows’, despite being used to sell a variety of goods such as gelato, bread, and other Italian delicacies. Even after falling out of use, and many being bricked up over the course of the next centuries, a few are still used today, and constitute a very memorable part of Florence’s 3000 year old wine story.</p>



<p></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>BAR HOPPING</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="768" src="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Babae.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-7163" style="width:250px" srcset="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Babae.jpg 1024w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Babae-300x225.jpg 300w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Babae-768x576.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p><strong>Babae Florence</strong></p>



<p>Location: Via Santo Spirito, 21R, 50125</p>



<p>Vibe: Cozy, intimate, elegant.</p>



<p>Known for: Probably Florence’s most famous ‘wine-window’, great selection of food &amp; wine.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" width="276" height="184" src="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/image-2.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-7157" style="width:250px"/></figure>



<p><strong>Enoteca Pitti Gola e Cantina</strong></p>



<p>Location: Piazza de' Pitti, 16, 50125</p>



<p>Vibe: Elegant, modest, welcoming.</p>



<p>Known for: Using ingredients and dishes from Tuscan regions, pairing them with wines from the same area.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" width="276" height="152" src="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/image-3.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-7159" style="width:250px"/></figure>



<p><strong>Vineria Sonora</strong></p>



<p>Location: Via degli Alfani, 39R, 50121</p>



<p>Vibe: Quaint, passionate, rustic, trendy.</p>



<p>Known for: Wide range of lesser-known producers, as well as many natural &amp; organic wines.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" width="256" height="171" src="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/image-4.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-7160" style="width:250px"/></figure>



<p><strong>First Glass</strong></p>



<p>Location: Lungarno degli Acciaiuoli, 6R, 50125</p>



<p>Vibe: Modern, oenophilic, educational.</p>



<p>Known for: Serving sample-bottles so you can try and learn about as many interesting wines as you want.<strong><br></strong></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>WINE AS ART</strong></p>



<p><strong>PRODUCER BIBI GRAETZ</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" width="601" height="401" src="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/image-1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-7161" style="width:500px" srcset="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/image-1.jpg 601w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/image-1-300x200.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 601px) 100vw, 601px" /></figure>



<p>As a city full of rich architecture and extensive museums, wine contributes a large part to Florence’s artistic tapestry. Last year, our Head of Operations, Sophie Burleigh travelled to Florence to visit one of our favourite innovative wineries, Bibi Graetz, and you can read the specifics of her trip <a href="https://cbwine.com/articles/bibi-graetz-and-the-art-of-winemaking/">here</a>. Bibi Graetz is first and foremost an artist; as the son of Swiss-Israeli sculptor Gidon Graetz, Bibi quickly gravitated towards the visual art mediums, thereafter becoming a painter himself, whose work can now be found adorning not only his bottles, but the many walls across his winery as well. When you experience Bibi’s wine’s, it is clear that this artistry, this passion for colour, tone, hue, texture, remains with him up to this day, and has simply found another suitable channel in the world of wine-making; with the grapes as his canvas, and his assiduously developed techniques as his brush, he continues to be just as evocative, passionate, and visionary in his wine as he was in his painting. Inside the brightly-labelled bottles, you will find wines as lush and impressionistic as the art which surrounds them.</p>



<p>One anecdote which I think captures Bibi’s passion and extravagance, surrounds a wine he released in 2020 entitled <em>‘Soffocone’</em>¸which, once you have acquired the translation, you will understand why there was a bit of a furore — one perhaps not helped by its label design: a tranquil storm of opulent curvature, swirled into the figure of woman, no doubt in preparation for the act the wine’s title refers to.</p>



<p>Only a 20-minute drive from Florence, Bibi Graetz is just one of the many amazing producers in the area willing and ready to accept visitors, and share their love for all things oenological. If you are interested in visiting Bibi Graetz, or any other wineries during your travels across, <a href="mailto:Info@cbwine.com">get in touch</a> and we will be more than happy to arrange an unforgettable journey for you.</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bibi Graetz and the Art of Winemaking</title>
		<link>https://cbwine.com/articles/bibi-graetz-and-the-art-of-winemaking/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sophie Burleigh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 09:43:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cbwine.com/?p=7141</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sitting in the tasting room of the Bibi Graetz winery in the heart of Fiesole, Italy, it is easy to be overcome by the panoramic view of Florence that expands before you. However, I found myself instead intrigued by one of the canvases adorning the tasting room wall, hung at the head of the tasting [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" width="484" height="647" src="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Bibi-1-2.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-7150" style="width:300px" srcset="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Bibi-1-2.jpg 484w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Bibi-1-2-224x300.jpg 224w" sizes="(max-width: 484px) 100vw, 484px" /></figure></div>


<p class="has-text-align-left">Sitting in the tasting room of the Bibi Graetz winery in the heart of Fiesole, Italy, it is easy to be overcome by the panoramic view of Florence that expands before you. However, I found myself instead intrigued by one of the canvases adorning the tasting room wall, hung at the head of the tasting table. An explosion of primary colours and texture, with capitalized text swiping into frame. The 20-year celebration canvas painted by winery owner Bibi Graetz himself, perfectly summarises the winery’s mastering of balance: balance between creativity and precision, between fun and elegance, between madness and sanity. These dichotomies, evident not only throughout the winery but also the history of Bibi Graetz, are what made my visit to the Bibi Graetz winery this Summer a truly momentous experience.</p>



<p>Turning to winemaking in the late 1990s, Bibi’s first love was for art. Son of Swiss-Israeli sculptor Gidon Graetz, Bibi followed in his father’s creative footsteps and graduated from Florence's Accademia dell'Arte. Despite Bibi’s shift into the world of wine appearing a sizable departure from art, much of what Bibi exemplified as an artist is evident also in his wines. &nbsp;Without following any DOC or DOGC regulations within the Toscana region, Bibi benefits from a unique freedom when it comes to crafting his wines. And despite his labels not featuring these certifications, the quality of his products has still garnered a wealth of attention, resulting in a cult, but ferocious, global Bibi Graetz following.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" width="931" height="698" src="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Bibi-2-1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-7151" style="width:400px" srcset="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Bibi-2-1.jpg 931w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Bibi-2-1-300x225.jpg 300w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Bibi-2-1-768x576.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 931px) 100vw, 931px" /></figure></div>


<p>During a recent trip to Tuscany, I was fortunate enough to visit the Bibi Graetz winery. Upon my arrival, I was greeted by winery employee Tatiana, whose passion and love for the brand was evident from the moment she first spoke. Meeting on the open-air deck on the east wing of the winery, where the wines’ grapes arrive for selection and sorting, I felt instantly immersed in the Bibi Graetz story, the atmosphere of winemaking already humming around me.</p>



<p>The building itself, although grandiose, doesn’t appear upon first sight as a winery. Located in the heart of the town of Fiesole, I initially walked right past, looking for a building resembling a warehouse or factory, rather than a beautiful Tuscan home. Upon entering the property, Tatiana justified my confusion; although a winery in its bottom levels, the first two floors of the house are in fact Bibi’s family home. Already I could feel this wouldn’t be the only surprise of the visit.</p>



<p>As we moved from room to room within the winery, the use of colour became abundantly clear and nothing short of spectacular. Walking past the grand piano gracing the entranceway to the belly of the property, each barrel storage room engulfs you in a different primary colour, denoting a different stage along the maturation process. The further I journeyed the more I realised colour was not to be the only quirk of the building.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" width="321" height="241" src="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/image-1.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-7143" style="width:400px" srcset="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/image-1.jpeg 321w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/image-1-300x225.jpeg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 321px) 100vw, 321px" /></figure></div>


<p>One of the storage rooms, holding huge floor to ceiling barrels, posed an interesting conundrum: How did the barrels get through the doorway? I shouldn’t have been shocked to learn that Bibi’s commitment to the process extends to carving a hole in the side of the building itself and rolling the barrels in, so as to situate them without upsetting the building regulations of the house. Following an immaculate cover-up, visitors would never know. Upon entering the fermentation room, I was lured into a false sense of normalcy, surrounded by stainless steel tanks and a calmer wall colour, only to then notice the disco ball hanging from the ceiling - a homage to the Italian nightclub that used to reside in the basement of the building.</p>



<p>The slight madness of the whole experience became intoxicating when paired with Tatiana’s impassioned stories and clear love for the wines and the process. Despite having worked with Bibi Graetz for only a few years, her deep knowledge of the history of the brand and devotion to the wines was clear. On her first day of employment at Bibi Graetz, Bibi decided to hold a vertical tasting of every vintage of Testamatta to date. Hearing about the experience, I could sense the wonder and enthusiasm that has blossomed right from her first day at the winery, persisting even now.</p>



<p>After being wowed by the labyrinth of technicolor winemaking rooms, I was lucky enough to enjoy a tasting, surrounded not only by Bibi’s captivating art on the walls, but by rare bottles, case collections and magnums, decorating the surfaces.&nbsp; An elite setting for an elite selection of wines: Testamatta Bianco 2022 / Colore Bianco 2022 / Testamatta 2021 / Colore 2021. Two pairs of wines offering a bright comparison, showing off the freshness and citrus of the Testamatta, against the richness and balanced minerality of the Colore. A stunning collection topped off with a special blind tasting of what turned out to be 2018 Testamatta, proving Bibi’s wines not only offer ripe, fresh flavours when young, but also age exceptionally.</p>



<p>Where Bibi offers traditionality and honours the Sangiovese, Ansonica and Inzolia grapes native to the region, he equally promotes a certain ‘craziness’ with his labelling. Testamatta literally translates to ‘crazy head’, and their Bollamatta sparkling to ‘crazy bubble’. This maverick approach to labelling is a striking departure from other producers of the region, and part of the reason they have stood out to international drinkers and investors, searching for stand-out brands. One bottle in particular, however, ruffled some international feathers with its labelling, pushing the envelope beyond endearing individuality. Their Soffocone red (with a not-so-PG translation), caused some stir with the artistic depiction of a naked woman on its label. It also featured a somewhat phallic shape in one of the corners, which proved too provocative for the US market. Instead of forgoing the market altogether, Bibi chose to eliminate the outline on bottles sold in the US, to maintain sales.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" width="462" height="634" src="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Bibi-4-1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-7152" style="width:200px" srcset="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Bibi-4-1.jpg 462w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Bibi-4-1-219x300.jpg 219w" sizes="(max-width: 462px) 100vw, 462px" /></figure></div>


<p>When selling to the Indian market, the brand was pleased to realise the phallic shape did not cause any issues for consumers. It was however, the naked woman herself that was rejected by Indian suppliers this time. But, in true problem-solving Bibi style, he hand-painted 2000 dresses onto the 2000 women on the labels making their way to be consumed by the Indian market.</p>



<p>This attention to detail and commitment to the highest standards of wine making and bottling, although Bibi’s personal ethos, extends to his entire team. Upon visiting the labelling factory on the day a large shipment of Testamatta was due to leave the premises, Bibi noticed a single bottle whose label was marginally off-center. All staff members were halted and the process of redoing every single label in the order ensued. &nbsp;It is this same perfectionist approach that is evident when exploring the winery itself. Every room, every painting, every label and wine, tells a story and makes sense within the ecosystem of Bibi Graetz.</p>



<p>Living above the winery, Bibi has successfully melded his family and professional life in more ways than one. For his Balocchi (toys) 2020 trilogy, released for the March 2023 edition of La Place de Bordeaux’s ‘beyond Bordeaux’ campaign, he involved his children in painting the labels for the bottles; His first daughter, Margherita, painting the Balocchi di Colore No. 1, his third daughter, Ingrid, the No. 3, and his youngest, 8-year-old, son, Ludovico the No. 8. With the stairs to Bibi’s home leading directly off the ground floor of the winery, the involvement of the winery in his home life and vice versa, is truly inspiring.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" width="291" height="258" src="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/image.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-7142" style="width:400px"/></figure></div>


<p>It is no wonder a flurry of suppliers and private investors flock to the Bibi Graetz website upon the release of all new vintages. After visiting Bibi Graetz and experiencing the expansive view of Florence Bibi gazes out upon whilst selecting his grape parcels, mixing and adding as a painter does with his paints, I can begin to understand the passion with which Bibi Graetz wines are created. Stocking Bibi Graetz wines at CB Uncorked has always been a privilege, but now holds even more weight having been able to appreciate and experience the finesse, the ‘craziness’, and the true artistry of Bibi Graetz.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>An Ode to Riesling</title>
		<link>https://cbwine.com/articles/an-ode-to-riesling/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sterling Weston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 17:46:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cbwine.com/?p=6025</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Wine comes in at the mouthAnd love comes in at the eye; —W.B. YEATS, A Drinking Song Exactly 590 years ago today, a humble cellar manager named Klaus Kleinfisch recorded the following in an invoice to his master, Count John IV of Katzenelnbogen: […] 22 ß umb seczreben rüßlingen in die wingarten. This is the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-right">Wine comes in at the mouth<br>And love comes in at the eye;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">—W.B. YEATS, <em>A Drinking Song</em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"></p>



<p>Exactly 590 years ago today, a humble cellar manager named Klaus Kleinfisch recorded the following in an invoice to his master, Count John IV of Katzenelnbogen:</p>



<p>           […]<em> 22 ß umb seczreben <strong>rüßlingen</strong> in die wingarten</em>.</p>



<p>This is the first mention we have of the now well-known Riesling, albeit in an archaic form.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">—</p>



<p>Revisiting its uncertain history is a great way to celebrate the Riesling grape, not only for an article regarding the wine, but for myself as well; it was <em>the</em> inaugural wine for me, the one that sparked my love for the drink. It was something about the aureate hue, the bright bouquet of the aroma, the effulgent acidity, followed by a surge of flavours I could not quite dissect until the third, fourth, maybe fifth sip: candied orchard fruits? honey? citrus? pebbles? hay? followed by this creamy, nutty flavour akin to a hazelnut-infused butter? …and then that oft-proclaimed ‘petrol’ note arrived.</p>



<p>Upon writing this article, I tried not to romanticise that sensory experience too much — but it is quite difficult to do so; and, given that the grape hails from the same land as Goethe, Schiller, and Novalis, I believe I can be forgiven…</p>



<p>This is not a rare sentiment, however; I think it is fair to say that Rieslings do tend to make a rather conspicuous first impression: they have this rare, almost dialectical ability to be overpowering, and yet extremely elegant at the same time. I remember David Kermode, in discussing the extravagance of Jancis Robinson’s tasting notes, facetiously conjured up the absurd and jestful tasting note ‘nubile ballerina’ — and yet this does, albeit in an unorthodox, crude, and almost contradictorily manner, capture something, some essence of that palatine dance of the Riesling. This complexity, this profundity comes, quite clearly, from its ability to possess the bright, citrusy, fruit-forward notes which belong to a cool-climate white wine, and yet, due to its naturally high levels of acidity (of course only heightened further by the altitudes and climates it usually finds itself in), it is able to mature in the bottle for considerably longer than we would find for say, a Sauvignon Blanc. This is, really, the charm of the Riesling. This maturation process becomes even more important for later ripening wines such as Spätlese, Auslese, or many of the other German wine classifications that designate post-ripeness grapes — but this deserves an article of its own.</p>



<p>Not long after Klaus Kleinfisch invoiced those 22 vines in Rüsselsheim, the name began to appear across Germany, Austria, and then, less than 50 years later, France. Now, we are accustom to seeing them all over the globe, most notably the U.S.A., Australia, and New Zealand; and in many ways this was a much welcomed journey for the Riesling, being as it is, a very ‘terroir-friendly’ varietal, one that has a distinct character, but one that can still be ‘shaped’, as it were, by its surroundings. Despite this immense talent and versatility, there is still nothing like a Riesling from its <em>Heimat, </em>and one of the most esteemed producers in Germany at the moment is Egon Müller, whose various Mosel vineyards are responsible for not only some of the best Rieslings, but some of the most accessible as well. The family’s first vineyard was acquired in 1797, and as such, over 17 generations have gone into making Weingut Egon Müller what it is today.</p>



<p>In particular, we offer two of their wonderful wines via our Uncorked website:</p>



<p>At the entry level, we have the <a href="https://cbuncorked.com/wine/egon-muller-scharzhof-qba-2021/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>Scharzhof QBA, 2021</strong></a>, which, whilst it has a few years on it, nevertheless displays those bright, fruit-driven flavours that any fan of Chardonnay and Sauvignon Blanc will feel at home with: apple, lime, blossoms, etc., but with a subtle complex minerality in the finish — one which defiantly embodies the slate-imbued soils of the Mosel Valley.</p>



<p>In addition, we offer the highly rated 2018 edition of the <a href="https://cbuncorked.com/wine/egon-muller-le-gallais-wiltinger-braune-kupp-riesling-auslese-mosel-2018/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>Le Gallais Wiltinger Braune Kupp Riesling Auslese</strong></a>: which, being an Auslese (affected by ‘Noble Rot’), is a wine with pronounced complexity, gradually stepping into the sweeter side, wherein you can find delicious stone-fruit notes such as peach, and apricot, as well as plenty of that characteristic mineral taste, all followed thereafter by a lingering aftertaste which trails fervently behind.</p>



<p>Not only are Rieslings regarded for their uniqueness, their willingness to reflect terroir, and their ability to age in the bottle, but they are famously great with many, many different foods. It is almost seen a staple ‘pairer’, given its prowess at meshing with a whole host of flavours and cuisines. The inherent balance of sweetness and acidity in any Riesling older than 2 years, finds its place alongside seafood, white meats like veal and chicken, spicy food, salty food, and, of course, purely by itself.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">—</p>



<p>Given the ostensible <em>poetry</em> of the Riesling, I think it is fitting to end with a verse from Novalis’ <em>Hymen an Die Nacht</em>, which beautifully likens the human experience itself to the ‘golden’ flow of a ‘life-wine’:</p>



<p></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Die Sternwelt wird zerfließen &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The starry-world will deliquesce</em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Zum goldnen Lebenswein, &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To the golds of this life’s wine,</em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Wir werden sie genießen&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Wherein we shall celebrate</em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Und lichte Sterne sein.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And like the stars shall shine.</em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">London, 13<sup>th</sup> March, MMXXV</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Limited-edition labels: Value in the visual</title>
		<link>https://cbwine.com/articles/limited-edition-labels-value-in-the-visual/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sophie Burleigh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 13:57:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cbwine.com/?p=5464</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Investing in fine wine has long been a proven strategy for wealth preservation and portfolio diversification. But does adding a limited-edition label truly enhance returns for investors, or is it simply a marketing ploy? Luxury wine brands like Dom Pérignon frequently release exclusive editions with unique packaging and collaborations—commanding higher initial prices. But do these [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Investing in fine wine has long been a proven strategy for wealth preservation and portfolio diversification. But does adding a limited-edition label truly enhance returns for investors, or is it simply a marketing ploy? Luxury wine brands like Dom Pérignon frequently release exclusive editions with unique packaging and collaborations—commanding higher initial prices. But do these bottles appreciate more than their standard counterparts of the same vintage over time? Do limited edition labels genuinely offer superior returns or does the hype outweigh investment potential?</p>



<p><strong>Performance of Fine Wine Investments</strong></p>



<p>Historically, fine wine investments have delivered consistent returns. Since 1988, the market has seen average annual returns of around 10%, with long-term investments yielding more stable outcomes. These returns are greatly due to the scarcity of fine wines across the globe and the finite amount of each vintage available. Operating on basic supply and demand principles, offerings from each vintage increase in collectability as they are consumed globally, increasing the rarity of any bottles left.</p>



<p>In a way, all bottles of fine wine are limited-edition, especially when looking at the production numbers of more cult producers. However, some wineries have taken to also releasing limited-edition labels and collaboration series. With wine already being limited vintage by vintage, it may be safe to assume that one vintage with altered labelling would not have a great influence on collectability, but re-sale prices of fine wines currently on the market with special labelling have proven this presumption false.&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Case Study: Dom Pérignon Special Editions</strong></p>



<p>Dom Pérignon, renowned for its vintage Champagnes, periodically releases limited-edition bottles that have garnered significant attention. Their collaboration with Andy Warhol for their 2000 vintage brut Champagne was the first of many celebrity partnerships, harmonising the artistry of Warhol’s works with that of the brand’s sparkling wine craftsmanship. The wine bottles were adorned with one of six pop-art labels, each a different bold colour in a ‘collection-them-all’ fashion. This marrying of the art and wine worlds continued through their collaborations with the likes of David Lynch, Jeff Koons, and Jean-Michel Basquiat to name a few. Not only through art, Dom Pérignon have also expressed the creativity of what they do through music, working with Lady Gaga, Lenny Kravitz and Björk.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" width="672" height="354" src="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Dom-P-2.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-5466" style="width:880px" srcset="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Dom-P-2.jpg 672w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Dom-P-2-300x158.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 672px) 100vw, 672px" /></figure>



<p></p>



<p></p>



<p>Taking a look at their most recent collaboration with Jean-Michel Basquiat for their 2015 vintage, bottles are currently being sold for around £220.00 per 75cl. When comparing this pricing to their standard 2015 label, selling for around £180.00, the price difference is distinct, but not worlds-apart. The question is, does this price disparity grow or shrink when the wine enters the secondary market, where prices are a distinct representation of what the market as a whole perceives the wine to be worth.</p>



<p>When looking at the comparative value of Dom Pérignon special releases vs. their standard edition counterparts, as is evident in the graphs below there is a difference in both value and fluctuation. Although the limited-edition labels offer higher overall value, their demand is much more variant throughout the years, as opposed to the less-wavering lower market value of the standard bottles.</p>



<p><strong>Dom Pérignon Andy Warhol 2000</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="442" src="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Dom-Perignon-Andy-Warhol-2000-Comparison-1024x442.png" alt="" class="wp-image-5467" srcset="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Dom-Perignon-Andy-Warhol-2000-Comparison-1024x442.png 1024w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Dom-Perignon-Andy-Warhol-2000-Comparison-300x129.png 300w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Dom-Perignon-Andy-Warhol-2000-Comparison-768x331.png 768w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Dom-Perignon-Andy-Warhol-2000-Comparison-1536x663.png 1536w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Dom-Perignon-Andy-Warhol-2000-Comparison-2048x884.png 2048w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Dom-Perignon-Andy-Warhol-2000-Comparison.png 2561w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p></p>



<p><strong>Dom Pérignon David Lynch 2003</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="442" src="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Dom-Perignon-David-Lynch-2003-Comparison-1024x442.png" alt="" class="wp-image-5468" srcset="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Dom-Perignon-David-Lynch-2003-Comparison-1024x442.png 1024w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Dom-Perignon-David-Lynch-2003-Comparison-300x129.png 300w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Dom-Perignon-David-Lynch-2003-Comparison-768x331.png 768w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Dom-Perignon-David-Lynch-2003-Comparison-1536x663.png 1536w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Dom-Perignon-David-Lynch-2003-Comparison-2048x884.png 2048w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Dom-Perignon-David-Lynch-2003-Comparison.png 2561w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p></p>



<p><strong>Dom Pérignon Bjork &amp; Chris Cunningham 2006</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="442" src="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Dom-Perignon-Bjork-Chris-Cunningham-2006-Comparison-1024x442.png" alt="" class="wp-image-5469" srcset="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Dom-Perignon-Bjork-Chris-Cunningham-2006-Comparison-1024x442.png 1024w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Dom-Perignon-Bjork-Chris-Cunningham-2006-Comparison-300x129.png 300w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Dom-Perignon-Bjork-Chris-Cunningham-2006-Comparison-768x331.png 768w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Dom-Perignon-Bjork-Chris-Cunningham-2006-Comparison-1536x663.png 1536w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Dom-Perignon-Bjork-Chris-Cunningham-2006-Comparison-2048x884.png 2048w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Dom-Perignon-Bjork-Chris-Cunningham-2006-Comparison.png 2561w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p></p>



<p><strong>Dom Pérignon Tokujin Yoshioka 2009</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="442" src="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Dom-Perignon-Tokujin-Yoshioka-2009-Comparison-1024x442.png" alt="" class="wp-image-5470" srcset="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Dom-Perignon-Tokujin-Yoshioka-2009-Comparison-1024x442.png 1024w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Dom-Perignon-Tokujin-Yoshioka-2009-Comparison-300x129.png 300w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Dom-Perignon-Tokujin-Yoshioka-2009-Comparison-768x331.png 768w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Dom-Perignon-Tokujin-Yoshioka-2009-Comparison-1536x663.png 1536w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Dom-Perignon-Tokujin-Yoshioka-2009-Comparison-2048x884.png 2048w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Dom-Perignon-Tokujin-Yoshioka-2009-Comparison.png 2561w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p></p>



<p>Standard vintage bottles of fine wines will always have their loyal fans and buyers, consistently stocking or drinking the brand and thus maintaining its market value. This is especially prevalent with non-vintage sparkling wines, as with blending, the quality of the wine year on year is less dependent on winemaking conditions. However, special labels always benefit from special marketing, aimed not at the brand’s loyal fans, but instead at the fans of the collaborating artist. This influx of attention on the wine at times of high marketing attracts an equally large influx of new buyers, causing those peaks in a wine’s value. But even without these peaks, the loyal fans of the wine brand are still purchasing what they would have, limited-edition label or not, maintaining that baseline value even when not marketed to new audiences.</p>



<p><strong>Entry-level products</strong></p>



<p>It is not only the top wines of fine wine brands boasting top-tier prices that benefit from releasing innovative new labelling. Many producers are also recognising the benefits for their entry-level products, more readily available in wine retail stores and supermarkets.</p>



<p>Australian winery Penfolds offer an extensive range of wines, with pricing from under £10 to back vintages auctioning for over $15,000.00 per bottle. Although their reach is already just about as wide as it could be, they frequently cast their net even further, with limited-edition releases and cases of their wines. They welcomed their first creative partner, NIGO, in 2023 whose wealth of creative experience spans art, fashion and music. Since then, NIGO has redesigned a range of Penfolds wines, including the first ever design takeover of their flagship ‘Grange’ wine.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="540" src="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/NIGO-1-1024x540.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-5471" srcset="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/NIGO-1-1024x540.jpg 1024w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/NIGO-1-300x158.jpg 300w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/NIGO-1-768x405.jpg 768w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/NIGO-1.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>By collaborating with NIGO, Penfolds is able to market their wines in fun and creative ways, being in no way bound to the limits of their own branding. The younger generation, perhaps unaware of the prestige of the Penfolds brand, are invited to try the wines without the pretense of brand recognition. And should they like them, this is another potential Penfolds customer for life. A bottle of Penfolds Grange by NIGO 2019 is currently selling for £750.00 at Hedonism (London), their standard counterpart, Penfolds Grange 2019 for just £575.00.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img decoding="async" width="426" height="473" src="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/NIGO-2.png" alt="" class="wp-image-5472" srcset="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/NIGO-2.png 426w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/NIGO-2-270x300.png 270w" sizes="(max-width: 426px) 100vw, 426px" /></figure></div>


<p>Supermarket brands also jumping onboard include the likes of 19 Crimes, launching a series of limited-edition ‘glow in the dark’ labels for Halloween last year. As with the wines of Penfolds, a consumer unaware of the 19 Crimes brand may just become an all-time fan after taking a punt on their quirky and eye-catching October release.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img decoding="async" width="653" height="328" src="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/19-Crimes.png" alt="" class="wp-image-5473" srcset="https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/19-Crimes.png 653w, https://cbwine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/19-Crimes-300x151.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 653px) 100vw, 653px" /></figure></div>


<p><strong>Investment potential</strong></p>



<p>Not just a fun visual component for the consumer, limited-edition labels also offer compelling investment opportunities to collectors. As exemplified by the Dom Pérignon graphs, the re-sale price of limited-edition bottles can be staggering if sold in periods of high demand or aggressive marketing. And even without these periods, the bottles rarely sink below the value of their standard counterparts.</p>



<p>To maximize returns on limited-edition wine resale, investors can strategically time their sales around key events related to the collaborating celebrity—such as album releases, film premieres, or anniversaries. Additionally, seasonal demand spikes, like holiday gifting periods or major cultural celebrations, can drive up interest. Growing acclaim for associated art, music, or design movements can also elevate a bottle’s prestige, making it even more desirable in secondary markets. By staying attuned to these trends, collectors can significantly enhance their returns on limited-edition bottles. And in the meantime, enjoy the limited-edition art on their wines. Special edition wine labels – not just a pretty picture.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
